Wei Jing ANG

E-mail: weijing.ang710@gmail.com | LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/wei-jing-ang

Nationality: Singaporean | Country of Residence: Singapore

PROFILE SUMMARY

As a fresh graduate with a degree in Earth Science, I have two publications in well-known peer-reviewed journals and three years of research experience in geospatial analysis, remote sensing, hydrology, and geomorphology. I value continuous learning and my key experiences are:

EXPERIENCE	DESCRIPTION	DURATION
Research 3 (under review)	Dams database and mapping	Aug 2022 – Present
Research 2 (published)	Remote sensing and hydrology	Aug 2021 – Aug 2022
Teaching Assistant	MATLAB programming	Aug 2021 – Nov 2021
Student Assistant	ArcGIS lab manuals development	Jul 2021 – Aug 2022
Research 1 (published)	Bathymetry mapping	Aug 2020 – Aug 2021
Student Research	Urban greenery and place identity	Jan 2018 – Sep 2018
Geospatial Intern	Geospatial start-ups	Nov 2017 – Dec 2017

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Environmental Earth Systems Science with Minor in Modern Languages (Japanese) Nanyang Technological University, Singapore	Aug 2019 – Jun 2023
Honours (Highest Distinction), GPA: 4.82/ 5.00, Specialisation: Geosciences Nanyang Scholarship • Dean's List • NTU President Research Scholar	
Singapore-Cambridge GCE Advanced Level Dunman High School, Singapore 8 Distinctions including H3 Geography • Academic Excellence Award	Jan 2013 – Dec 2018

RESEARCH & PUBLICATION

Dams in the Mekong: A comprehensive database, spatiotemporal distribution and hydropower potentials | Nanyang Technological University

Aug 2022 – Present

Ang, W. J., Park, E., Tran D. D., Loc, H. H., & Pokhrel, Y. (2023). Dams in the Mekong: A comprehensive database, spatiotemporal distribution, and hydropower potentials. [Preprint under review by Earth System Science Data].

- Integrated dam databases through GIS, R programming and Microsoft Excel
- Conducted spatiotemporal analysis of the dams to determine future dam growth
- Evaluated grid-based basin-wide hydropower potential using modelled discharge

Geomorphic control on stage-area hysteresis in three of the largest floodplain lakes | Nanyang Technological University

Aug 2021 – Aug 2022

Ang, W. J., Park, E., & Yang, X. (2022). Geomorphic control on stage-area hysteresis in three of the largest floodplain lakes. *Journal of Hydrology*, *614*, 128574.

- Best Poster Award (Natural and Physical Sciences) and Journal Publication Award
- Extracted the area of lakes from MODIS satellite imagery through ArcGIS
- Analysed lake behaviour and quantified hysteresis through integration in MATLAB
- Discussed the influence of geomorphology and lake-river connectivity on hysteresis

Mapping floodplain bathymetry in the middle-lower Amazon River using Inundation Frequency Nanyang Technological University Ang, W. J., Park, E., & Alcantara, E. (2021). Mapping floodplain bathymetry in the middle-lower Amazon River using inundation frequency and field control. Geomorphology, 392, 107937. Received the Research Excellence Award and Journal Publication Award Derived the floodplain bathymetry of the Amazon River using ArcGIS Analysed grain-size distribution and validated bathymetry through MATLAB	Aug 2020 – Aug 2021
 The role of skyrise greenery in sustainable living and place-making Dunman High School • GCE A Level H3 Geography (distinction) Investigated the relationship between biophilic urbanism and place-making Conducted independent fieldwork involving participant and site observations Interviewed residents, a government personnel and an urban design professor 	Jan 2018 – Sep 2018
EXPERIENCE	
 Volunteer Japanese Student Guide Team Azuchi Guided Japanese students to attractions, on company visits, and for school projects Communicated with the students in Japanese to facilitate cultural exchange Planned and improvised routes based on the students' needs and time constraints 	Jan 2019 – Present
 Student Assistant (GIS) Nanyang Technological University Developed 6 detailed ArcGIS lab manuals and designed figures for teaching Presented research experiences involving GIS to students as a guest speaker Reviewed, edited, and reorganised a manuscript about hydrology 	Jul 2021 – Aug 2022
 Teaching Assistant (MATLAB) Nanyang Technological University Prepared materials, graded assignments and taught in class to facilitate learning Actively sought out and guided students who were struggling Worked closely with the professor and other teaching assistants to run the course Received positive feedback from students for patiently clearing their doubts 	Aug 2021 – Nov 2021
 Publicity Director NTU Japanese Appreciation Club Collaborated with different departments to maintain a positive club image Led the publicity team to ensure efficient internal and external communication by managing the social media sites and the mass email marketing platform 	May 2020 – April 2021
 Geospatial Intern Singapore Land Authority Designed a mock website aimed at promoting local geospatial start-ups Researched on trends and supporting policies in geospatial and innovative industries to propose strategies for stimulating the local geospatial industry Part of the Ministry of Education Geography Talent Development Programme 	Nov 2017 – Dec 2017
 Volunteer Project Leader Make A Wish Foundation and Citi-YMCA Youth for Causes Organised sales and a carnival to raise \$\$6000 and spread awareness for ill children Led the planning team and student volunteer team to execute the activities Negotiated with sponsors to secure deals, including a carnival and a free venue 	Mar 2017 – Sep 2017